# Paul Mora

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Scientist and Econometrician with 3+ years experience. Focused on statistical analysis and time series forecasting models in Python. Experienced at explaining technical topics to a non-technical audience. Founder of two Start-ups, fluent in English and German, Data Science Teacher and University of Oxford Alumni.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python (incl. Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, PyTorch, NLTK), R, SQL, Julia
- + 30 Selected Machine Learning Projects/ Articles (+2500 monthly readers) to be found here 🗷 🖸

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## STATWORX, Frankfurt

April 2021 - Present

Data Science Consultant

At STATWORX I work as a Data Science Consultant, currently leading a team of three to implement a recommender system for a large German car manufacturer. Herein we use the driving behavior of an individual to predict the best suited in-car software application for the driver. Additionally to the project work, I engage in the STATWORX Academy and regularly teach Python Programming to an audience of ten to twenty participants.

Furthermore, I lead the recruiting support of STATWORX, conducting interviews and coding challenges.

## Data Science Retreat, Berlin

September 2019 - Present

Data Science Teacher

• Teaching Python programming to a bootcamp of ten to fourteen students

## data4help, Berlin

May 2020 - Present

Co-Founder & Data Scientist

• Co-Founded a skill-based volunteering company helping non-profits to make use of their data

# Oxera Consulting LLP, Berlin/London

October 2019 - March 2021

Data Scientist & Economic Consultant

- Constructed a forecasting model for the price path of pharmaceutical drugs within a litigation.
- Analyzed the level of potential market power within a hospital merger in the UK.

## STUDY42, Frankfurt

November 2018 - January 2020

Founder & Teacher

• Independently founded a tutoring company, hired and managed team of eight tutors

#### German Central Bank, Frankfurt

August 2017 - August 2018

Data Analyst & Economist 🗷

• Predicted capital buffers of the European Insurance sector to aid macroprudential regulation

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Oxford, Oxford

2018 - 2019

Master of Science - Financial Economics - Dean's List & Distinction

# Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt

2014 - 2017

Bachelor of Science - Economics - Dean's List & Distinction